KristijanPerusko

software engineer

Contact

kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

Links

Linkedin:// kperusko Github:// kperusko Bitbucket:// kperusko

Languages

English, Croatian

Programming

Experience using: PHP, JavaScript HTML & CSS

Familiar with: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

Db

MongoDB, MySQL

Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

Additional

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

Summary

I've worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer. I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations, because I find them more challenging and therefore more interesting. This said, I would love to work more with functional programming.

Experience

2008-2014 **Novatec**In-house software engineer for my first two years. Became team leader building client's booking system and multiple customer-facing sites. Also served as project leader where I gathered requirements from clients, mentored junior engineers,

leader where I gathered requirements from clients, mentored junior engineers, planned and implemented critical features. My responsibilities included administration and optimization of MongoDB and MySQL DBs and Ubuntu/Debian servers.

2007-2008 **Tempo** IT administrator

Responsible for Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

2005-2007 Vlado elektronika

Sofware and electrical QA engineer aided testing of intrusion alarm

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time by 60%.

Education

2013	BS of information tehnology Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework	Veleuciliste u Rijeci (Rijeka College)
2002	Electrical engineering DC servo driver controlled by IR remote	Mate Blazina High School

Courses online

07 2014	M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations <i>MongoDB</i>	MongoDB
11 2013	Principles of Reactive Programming École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne	Coursera
10 2013	Machine Learning Stanford University	Coursera
10 2013	Interactive Programming in Python Rice University	Coursera
10 2013	M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers MongoDB	MongoDB
09 2013	Functional Programming Principles in Scala <i>Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne</i>	Coursera
06 2013	Startup Engineering Stanford University	Coursera